http://www.redwoodcu.org/about-rcu/security-privacy-deposit-insurance

Health Savings Accounts
Individual Retirement Accounts (IRA)
Auto Center & Services
RCU Auto Services (RCUAS)
Login Here
The size of your browser is more conducive to using our Mobile Banking website.
Open an Account
About RCUWhy RCUWhy RCULearn why Redwood Credit Union is a smart choice for banking services in the North Bay and San Francisco.
Our values include service, trust, people and cooperation. OverviewOur Vision and MissionRCU HistoryLeadershipAwardsOverviewOur Vision and MissionRCU HistoryLeadershipAwardsThe Credit Union DifferenceThe Credit Union DifferenceLearn more about how credit unions differ from banks, and how you can benefit from becoming a Credit Union Member. Learn about credit union advocacy.
The Credit Union Difference OverviewCredit Union HistoryAdvocacyThe Credit Union Difference OverviewCredit Union HistoryAdvocacyRCU PublicationsRCU PublicationsRedwood Credit Union (RCU) is committed to keeping our Members informed and up-to-date on important Credit Union news, information and specials. NewslettersNewslettersFor the PlanetFor the PlanetAs a socially conscious organization, Redwood Credit Union is committed to earth-friendly business practices that benefit the environment for generations to come.ServicesPartnersGo Green TipsRecognitionServicesPartnersGo Green TipsRecognitionBranch Locations & HoursShared Branch & ATMs AccessShared Branch & ATMs AccessGo to Shared Branch & ATMs AccessMember Services & Contact InformationContact UsRCU Community ProgramsPress RoomCareersSecurity, Privacy & Deposit InsuranceSecurity CenterSecurity CenterExplore our Security Center to learn more about fraud, with information about the latest scams and how you can safeguard your information. Go to Security CenterNews & Notes Redwood ReviewRedwood ReviewRedwood Review Spring 2020.
A Publication for Members of Redwood Credit Union. CEO Message, Corona Virus Response Assistance, Bank Securely at Home, Annual Meeting Update. Go to Redwood Review
< Additional About RCU
Popular Related Searches
Employment Development Department (EDD) Payments and Direct Deposit FAQs
What is Redwood Credit Union's routing and transit (ABA) number?
Redwood Credit Union's privacy policy
Home/ About RCU/ Security, Privacy & Deposit Insurance
Text Size
A
A
A
Security, Privacy & Deposit Insurance
request more information
We are committed to
your financial security
Our high-tech, secure
systems safeguard information
We make tools
available to monitor your account Explore our Security Center to learn more
Overview ID Theft Our Privacy Policy
NCUA Info
RCU takes extensive measures to protect the security of your accounts. Despite our best efforts, fraud can occur.
If you believe you’ve been a victim of account fraud or identity theft, please contact us immediately.
Account Protection
You can take an active role in monitoring and protecting your account using these tools and tips:
Alerts: Use RCU’s Online Banking to sign up for free instant emails about your account activity
eStatements: Review all transactions on your account with RCU’s free eStatements
Reporting Fraud
During business hours: 1 (800) 479-7928
After-Hours Fraud Reporting and Authorization Issues
Visa Debit Card:         1 (800) 479-7928
Visa Credit Card:        In the U.S. – 1 (888) 918-7313
Outside the U.S. – 1 (727) 299-2449 (You may call collect.)
Reporting Email Abuse or Suspected Phishing Attempts
Have you received a suspicious email? Or do you believe you’ve been contacted by us but you’re suspicious of the email’s origin? Please forward a copy of the email or Phishing website to fraud@redwoodcu.org. If you have other questions, please call us at 1 (800) 479-7928 or (707) 545-4000.
If you’re concerned that you’ve been a victim of identity theft, contact Redwood Credit Union first and then take these steps:
Contact the fraud departments at the major credit bureaus below. Request a “Fraud Alert” status be placed on your file and ask for free copies of your credit report.
Equifax, 1 (800) 525-6285
Experian, 1 (888) 397-3742
TransUnion, 1 (800) 680-7289
Contact the financial institution where you hold accounts or loans that you believe have been compromised.
File a report with your local police department.
Please read more
about our privacy policy about how Redwood Credit Union and RCU Services Group use your personal information.
Are my account balances insured, and if so, for how much?
Redwood Credit Union's deposit accounts are federally insured by the NCUA for a minimum of $250,000. However, insurance can often be increased depending on the way an account is structured.
Below are examples of the insurance provided for various types of accounts:
Individual accounts without a pay on death beneficiary: $250,000
Joint or Multi-owner accounts without a pay on death beneficiary: $250,000 per owner
Trust account or accounts with pay on death beneficiaries: $250,000 per beneficiary for each account owner.
Business accounts: $250,000
IRA accounts: $250,000
Basics of Structuring Accounts to Maximize Insurance
Different account numbers or different shares with the same ownership at the same institution is not enough to expand NCUA insurance beyond the standard $250K. As long the ownership of accounts are the same, they all are combined together for insurance purposes. The key is to change ownership structures.
Some easy ways to maximize coverage through different ownership are:
First and foremost: having beneficiaries (which we offer on all standard Membership and trust accounts). Pay on death beneficiary accounts are insured for $250K per beneficiary, per Account owner. For example, if the Member and her husband opened an account listing their 3 kids as beneficiaries, the account would be insured for $1.5 M ($250K X 6).
Next, each of the following types of accounts are insured entirely separately:
Individual
Joint
Trust/Pay on Death Beneficiary
Business
For Example: If the Member has an individual account with no beneficiary, and a joint account with his wife with no beneficiaries, that’s 2 different ownership types and would total $750K in insurance ($250K for the individual, $250K per owner on the joint).
These are just some very common examples, but there are many others. The key takeaway is that we can almost always find a way to ensure Members are fully covered. While it can sometimes be a bit confusing, using the Share Insurance Estimator tool is a great option as it customizes the coverage for the Member(s) for their situation.
Tools/Resources:
NCUA “Share Insurance Estimator” allows Members to calculator their insurance https://www.mycreditunion.gov/protect/Pages/SI.aspx
Related Links
Credit and Debit Card Security Information
Alerts eStatements
Join RCU Today
Welcome!Get started nowJoin Now
If you're interested in opening a Business, Trust, or other type of account, please visit your nearest branch.Redwood Credit Union serves anyone living, working or owning a business in California’s Northern Bay Area, which includes the counties of Sonoma, Marin, Napa, Mendocino, Lake, San Francisco, Contra Costa and Solano. We look forward to serving you!
Choose Account Type
Welcome!Choose the Type of Account You Wish to OpenPersonal
Youth If you're interested in opening a Business, Trust, or other type of account, please visit your nearest branch.
Login Help
Need Help Logging in to RCU Online?
If you’ve forgotten your RCU Online banking Username, password, or other login information, follow the directions below to get help now.
Forgot Username?
Forgot Password?
Learn More About Online Banking
Sign up today for RCU Online banking.
enroll now
Still need help?
Contact our Member Service Center at 1 (800) 479-7928, Monday through Friday from 7am to 8pm or Saturday from 8am to 5pm PST.
PersonalMembershipCheckingSavingsHome Loan CenterInvestment & Wealth ManagementVisa Credit and Debit CardsRedwood RewardsLoansInsuranceAuto Center & ServicesOnline, Mobile & ATMsForms & ApplicationsPersonal Rates
BusinessMembershipCheckingSavingsInvestment ServicesCredit and Debit CardsLoansInsuranceAuto Center & Services Payroll Services Merchant ServicesOnline & eServices Business RatesSelect Employer Group Program
Popular Related Searches
How do I enroll in RCU Online banking if I'm not a current RCU Online user?
What should I do with my check after making a mobile deposit ?
Home Loan Center
Set Up Account Alerts
See All
Ready to get started? Open an RCU account now!
Financial WellnessGet StartedSaveSpendBorrowPlanEn EspañolVideosCalculatorsResource Center
Popular Related Searches
What are some useful tools to create and maintain a budget?
Understanding FICO® Scores
Is It Time to Refinance Your Auto Loan?
Nine Ways to Master Your Money
See All
Ready to get started? Open an RCU account now!
About RCUWhy RCUThe Credit Union DifferenceRCU PublicationsFor the Planet
Employment Development Department (EDD) Payments and Direct Deposit FAQs
What is Redwood Credit Union's routing and transit (ABA) number?
Redwood Credit Union's privacy policy
Is my Member number the same thing as my account number?
See All
Ready to get started? Open an RCU account now!
